Garrett, Evan
Full Stack Web Developer
North Carolina, USA
D.O.B: 22 May 1991
American Citizen
evang522@gmail.com
github.com/evang522
linkedin.com/in/evang522
evanhgarrett.com



EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer October 2017-Present Freelance

- Created more than 6 full-stack Javascript projects running in production.
- Developed an application to solve an administrative need that is currently in use by family members.
- Worked on teams of 2-5 developers to create applications intended to meet real-world needs, making use of test suites with mocha and chai, continuous integration with TravisCl, and deployment with Heroku and Netlify.

Desktop Engineer

November 2015-October 2017 Athens Micro

- Played a considerable tech role in a growing business IT company, supporting over 300 businesses in the Southeast United States.
- Onsite and remotely managing and troubleshooting business computer networks, network technology, web, ftp, active directory, and file servers, and performing business disaster recovery ops.
- Enforcing and supporting best practices in computer networks for companies with more than 200 employees.
- Individually responsible for leading proactive and responsive tech support for more than 15 of the company's client businesses.

Student Technician May 2013 - May 2014
Toccoa Falls College

- Maintained Staff, Faculty, and Library Computer Technology.
- Responsible for responding to systems down issues in education buildings.
- Contributed to College Research regarding Library and Staff technology integration.

Student Technician

July 2009- May 2010

Armstrong Atlantic State University

- Maintained Computer Lab, Staff, and Faculty computer hardware and software.
- Set up and relocated workstations for faculty.
- Resolved issues with computer lab software and hardware for students.

ABOUT ME

My name is Evan and I am a Full stack web developer excelling in the creation of Node.js, React, MongoDB, and PostgresQL applications. With a strong background in IT support, I am also experienced with business technology management and computer networking. Technical problem solving and fixing broken code is one of my favorite things to do. I am a natural leader when I see the need arise and I love to creatively solve the kind of problems developers are always encountering.

Apart from writing code, my passions lie in philosophy, history, language-learning, culture, and hiking. On the weekends I can usually be found outside on a trail with my wife, reading a good book, or working very late into the night on a coding project I'm excited about.

EDUCATION

Engineering Immersion Graduate

Thinkful November 2017-May 2018

- Full Stack Engineering course specializing in best practice MongoDB, PostgreSQL Node, Express, React, and Redux application development.
- Emphasis on data science and implementing application data flow with efficiency.

Bachelor of Science in Philosophy

Toccoa Falls College August 2010-May 2014

- Major: Focus on Analytic Philosophy, Philosophy of Religion, Metaphysics, Politics, and Ethics
- Minor: Counseling Psychology

High School Diploma

Savannah Christian Preparatory School August 2005-May 2009

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Database
Application Logic
Frontend
CI & Deploy
Workflow

MongoDB, Mongoose.js, PostgresQL, Knex.js Node.js, Express.js, Socket.io, JWT Authentication, Python React.js, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3 Travis CI, Netlify, AWS, Heroku git, npm, yarn, Github, Bitbucket

LANGUAGES SPOKEN

English German Spanish Native Speaker Limited Working Proficiency Limited Working Proficiency

Drystore

Node.js, MongoDB, Pug, jQuery, Passport.js

- The Drystore was the first full stack app I created, having taught myself most of technologies necessary to write it: Javascript, Node, Express, Pug, and jQuery. I continue to improve it with the skills and knowledge from Thinkful.
- A platform for documenting and tracking information about stored dried food units.
- Allows users to perform CRUD operations on stored units as well as providing analytics about the amount of sustenance the store can provide for a specified number of people.
- Allows for different security roles amongst users, protecting data while allowing guests to view contents and analytics.

Tekteilen

Node.js, PostgreSQL, React.js, Redux, Custom JWT Auth Middleware, Github, Kanban

- I was the sole developer on this project, writing the full stack and working with SQL connecting to Node and React to accomplish a smooth data flow.
- This app makes use of custom written JWT authentication middleware I designed in order to have full control over the authentication process.
- Tekteilen is a service connecting organizations in need of web work with tech volunteers.
- Provides volunteer techs the ability to describe their skills, then search for projects that match their skills
- Provides non-profit and charity organizations the opportunity to sign up and post projects which will show up in the list of publicly available projects for techs.

Linklib

Python 3, Flask, Custom JWT Auth Middleware, React.js

- Linklib is a result of my taking a week to learn Python. I made use of Flask http framework for Python, building a REST API supporting a purely React frontend.
- I took the time to research the creation of custom-coded JWT authentication with Flask and wrote another implementation of this concept in Python for Linklib.
- A platform for storing, accessing, and playing back MP3 Links.
- Allows users to store links to hosted MP3 files in a personal portal while sharing them publicly.
- Provides a playback module that allows users to listen to audio while working or driving.